sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
the "impulses" that makes you want to meet it
aitaku naru no shoudou
the "innocence" that makes you want to cry
nakitaku naru no junjou
they've gone into the summer fire
natsu no hi ni tobikonda
the fireflies aren't coming back
hotaru wa kaeranai
you didn't say a single word and left a kiss for me behind
anata wa nanimo iwazu kuchizuke wo nokoshite
and nodded as you still got burned
kitsuzuku mama unazuita ne
it was so sad that my life was wavering
kanashii hodo inochi yurameiteita
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
sha la la my sweet lovely dear
sha la la itoshiki hito
I can also see you right now
anata mo mieteiru no
the dazzling moon will softly
mabayui tsuki ga sotto
illuminate the morning day
ashita wo terashite
and strongly and strongly shine on
tsuyoku tsuyoku kagayaite
Tales of a Gutsy Ninja
- Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls - Part 2
この戦い
おそらく 木ノ葉隠れの勝利だ。
I predict the Hidden Leaf shall
emerge victorious from this battle.
お前たちは
生かしておいてやろう。
Therefore, I shall let you three live.
情けはいらねえ！
We don't want your sympathy!
We can still fight!
まだまだ戦える！
よせ 自来也！
Jiraiya, stop!
お前たち３人は強い。
You three are strong...
そして ここでさえも生き残った。
You survived even this battleground.
この半蔵 これよりお前たちを
木ノ葉の三忍と呼び称えよう。
I, Hanzo, hereby name you
the "Hidden Leaf's Sannin".
命の代償に それぞれ名を名乗れ。
In exchange for your lives,
tell me your names.
木ノ葉の勝利で終わるのかのぉ。
Will it really end with
the Hidden Leaf's victory like he said?
アイツが言ったように。
そうしたら どうする？
And if it does, then what?
Will you set out on another journey?
また旅に出るのか？
そうじゃのう。
Maybe...
また旅に出て 本でも書くかのぉ。
Set out on my travels and
write another book...
なぜ 里に落ち着かない？
Why won't you settle down
in the village?
まだ出会っておらんような
気がする…。
I feel as though
I haven't encountered it yet.
例の運命ってヤツか？
You mean, your destiny?
シッ！
Quiet!
まだ子供だの。
油断するな。
They're just kids.
Don't let your guard down.
子ネズミでも
雨隠れの里の者だろう。
Even little mice can be from
the Hidden Rain Village.
隠れてないで 出てきなさい！
Don't hide. Show yourself!
なんだ？ お前…。
(弥彦)食べ物を分けてくれ。
What do you want?
Give me some food!
親は どうした？
What about your parents?
この戦争で忍に殺された。
They were killed by ninja
because of this war.
ほら 乾パンだ。
Here... have some bread.
長門 小南 出てこい！
Nagato, Konan, come on out!
They don't seem like bad guys.
悪いヤツらじゃなさそうだ！
Hey!
う～ん…。
食べ物は さっきやったろ！
なんで ついてくる！
We already gave you food!
Why are you following us?!
(小南)ありがとう。 これ お礼。
Thank you. This is for you...
折り紙だよ。 乾パンの包み紙で。
It's origami...
folded from the bread wrapping.
これを 私たちに？
This is for us?
オレたちに 忍術を教えてくれ。
Teach us ninjutsu...
アンタたち 木ノ葉の忍だろ？
You're all ninja from
the Hidden Leaf, right?
殺す？ この子たち。
Shall I kill these children?
Wha--?!
ずいぶん 戦争孤児を
見てきたけど むごいものよ。
I've seen many war orphans.
It's pitiful.
いっそのこと
ここで殺してやるのが➡
They would be better off
この子たちにとっても…。
if we just put them out of
their misery right now...
よせ！ 大蛇丸！
お前は 綱手と先に帰ってろ。
Orochimaru, enough!
You go on ahead with Tsunade.
わしは しばらく
コイツらの面倒を見る。
I'll stay here and look after them
for a while.
はぁ!?
Huh?!
多少 自立ができるように
なるまでだがな。
Just until they can take better
care of themselves...
これが せめてもの償いだ。
It is the least I can do.
しかし…。
But...
《これもまた 運命だ》
This is also part of destiny...
(みんな)いただきます！
Thank you for the food!
火遁の術一発で 焼き魚だな。
アハハハ！
Grilled fish in an instant with
my Fire Style Jutsu.
ん～ うまい！
Mm... Delicious!
先生 オレ 釣りのコツを覚えたぜ。
Sensei! I've gotten the hang of fishing!
ん？
Hmm?
長門 どうした？
What's the matter, Nagato?
(長門)家族のこと
思い出しちゃって そしたら…。
I just remembered my family...
And...
泣くな！ 男だろ！
Stop crying! You're a man!
そんなんだから
雨隠れの男は弱虫だと思われる！
It's because of guys like you
that men of the Hidden Rain
are considered cowards!
雨隠れを囲む三大国は
今は安定していないがの➡
Things are unstable among
three of the Great Nations
that surround the Hidden Rain Village.
この戦争も そう長くは続かん。
But this war won't drag out much longer.
お前たちが 大きくなる頃には
国々もわかりあい➡
By the time you are grown,
there will be mutual understanding
and peace will-
ここにも平和が…。
そんなの勝手だよ！
That's not fair!
オレらは 皆 家族を殺されたんだ。
We all lost our families!
わかりあうなら
相手を同じめに遭わせてからだ！
If there is a mutual understanding,
it's only after they go through
what we did!
それが 痛み分けってことだろ！
That's what it means to get even, right?!
でも そんなのムリだってことくらい
わかってる。
But... I know that's impossible.
だから 戦争はなくならないんだ。
That's why wars will never end!
雨は嫌いだ。
この国は いつも泣いている。
I hate rain.
This land is always crying.
弱虫だ。
It's a coward!
オレが この国を変えてやるんだ。
I'm gonna change this land.
みんなを守る！
I'll protect everyone!
だから 自来也先生。
That's why Jiraiya-sensei...!
Please teach us ninjutsu!
オレたちに 忍術の修業を
つけてくれ！
ハァ…。
《なかなか 小説のアイデアが
浮かばぬなぁ》
I don't have any ideas for my novel...
((わかりあうなら
相手を同じめに遭わせてからだ！
If there is a mutual understanding,
it's only after they go through
what we did!
だから 戦争はなくならないんだ！
That's why wars will never end!
(みんなを守る！))
I'll protect everyone!!
《主人公には
その憎しみを消して➡
I want the hero to wipe away
the hatred and bring about peace...
平和を作り上げてほしいのだが…。
はて どうすれば…》
Now then... how can I...?
自来也先生 大変！
Jiraiya-sensei, help!
Yahiko and Nagato are in trouble...!
弥彦と長門が！
案内しろ 小南！
Lead the way, Konan!
先生を連れてきたわ！
I brought Sensei!
何があった!?
What happened?
オレたちに 食料か 金目のものを
出せって 忍の残党が…。
This...
This leftover ninja told us to hand
over our food... and valuables.
そしたら 長門のヤツが…。
Then Nagato...
《コイツは 岩隠れの中忍か…。
He's a chunin from the Hidden Stone...
いったい どうやって？》
How did Nagato...?
《こ この目は…。
Th-Those eyes...!
この子 まさか…!?》
He couldn't... possibly be...!
《あの形状 あの波紋模様…
信じられん…。
That shape... That ripple pattern...
I can't believe it!
あの眼 三大瞳術のなかでも
最も崇高とされる眼 輪廻眼。
That eye...
Said to hold the most noble of
the three great Visual Jutsu...
忍の始祖とされる六道仙人。
The Rinnegan!
The Sage of the Six Paths,
said to be the father of all ninja...
現在のすべての忍術は
その輪廻眼を持つ仙人により➡
It is said that the Sage possessing
the Rinnegan eye
生み出されたと聞く。
developed all the jutsu known to us today.
それは 世が乱れたときに
天より遣わされる創造神とも➡
Rumored to always appear
when the world becomes corrupt,
すべてをゼロに戻す
破壊神ともいわれる。
capable of being both
a godlike force of creation
and an all-obliterating instrument
of destruction.
神話のような話だと
思っていたが➡
I always believed it as a mere legend.
本当に輪廻眼を持つ者が
存在するとは》
But here is someone who actually
possesses the Rinnegan!
((では伝える。
I shall now tell you...
In my dream...
ワシの夢では エロいだけのお主も
いずれ立派な忍になり➡
You, who are solely pervy, will still manage
to become a splendid ninja.
そして 一人前に
弟子を持つことになるのじゃが➡
And in time, you will have
your own disciple...
その弟子は将来 忍の世に
大きな変革をもたらす忍になる。
That disciple will become a ninja who
will bring about a great change
to the ninja world.
夢では そう見えた。
That is what I saw in my dream.
お主は その変革者を導く者じゃ。
You will guide that revolutionary...
(いずれ お主には大きな選択を
迫られる時がくるじゃろう))
The day will come when you will be
forced to make a critical selection.
《ひょっとしたら
長門が その変革者…》
Could Nagato be this revolutionary?
《運命に出会えたのかもしれん》
Perhaps I have found my destiny.
お前たちに
忍術を教えてやることにした。
I've decided to teach you ninjutsu.
ホントか？
この前のように➡
R-Really?!
いつ命の危険が
あるやも知れんからの。
You may encounter another life-threatening
situation like that last time.
己の身を守るための忍術だ。
It is ninjutsu for self-defense.
よ～し。
Yes!
この前は助けてくれて
ありがとうな 長門。
Thanks for saving us last time, Nagato!
Sorry I called you a coward!
弱虫とか言って悪かった。
何かあったら 今度はオレが
長門を助けてやるからな。
Next time anything happens,
I'll protect you!
あ ありがとう 弥彦。
Th-Thanks, Yahiko.
えぇ でも 弥彦より
長門のほうが強いんだよ。
Huh...? But Nagato is stronger
than you, Yahiko!
これから修業して強くなんだよ。
小南はひと言多いよ。
I'm gonna train starting now
and I'll become stronger!
You always exaggerate, Konan!
よ～し じゃあ始めるか。
All right, let's start!
最初は チャクラを練る修業だ。
The first lesson is on molding chakra.
(弥彦たち)はい 先生。
- Yes, Sensei!
(長門)うっ うっ…。
うっ うっ…。
なにかあるようだの。 言ってみろ。
Something's bothering you, eh?
先生。
この前のことか？
Talk to me.
Sensei...
Is it about that incident?
あのとき
弥彦が傷つけられたとき➡
That day...
When that man hurt Yahiko,
I was so mad at him.
ものすごく相手に腹が立ったんだ。
頭が真っ白になって
無我夢中で…。
Everything went blank in my head...
I didn't know what I was doing.
それで 気がついたら
相手は倒れてた。
Before I realized it, the man was dead...
そのあと すごく怖くなったんだ。
After that, I got so scared.
憎くて 我を忘れてボクが相手を…。
This hatred made me lose myself...
and I killed someone.
ボクのしたことは間違ってて。
ホントは もっといい方法が…。
What I did was wrong!
There had to be a better way--!
長門 ワシも それが正しいのか
間違っているのか よくわからん。
Nagato...
I really don't know
if it was right or wrong.
だが お前のおかげで
弥彦は死なずにすんだ。
But thanks to you, Yahiko didn't die.
友達を守った。
お前は正しいことをしたはずだ。
You protected your friend.
That had to be the right thing to do.
誰もお前を責められはしないのぉ。
No one can blame you for that.
傷つけられれば憎しみを覚える。
When you are hurt, you learn to hate.
逆に人を傷つければ恨まれるし
罪悪感にもさいなまれる。
On the other hand, when
you hurt someone, you are resented.
But you start to feel guilty as well.
だが そういう痛みを
知っているからこそ➡
Understanding such pain enables
you to be kind to others...
人に優しくできることもある。
それが 人だ。
That's what makes us human.
それって どういうこと？
What do you mean by that...?
成長するってことだのぉ。
It's called growing up.
成長するって
つまり どういうこと？
Growing up? What do you mean?
どうするか自分で考えることだ。
That, you need to figure out yourself.
弥彦は ボクと小南が
お腹を空かせて泣いてるときに➡
Konan and I were crying
because we were so hungry
助けてくれた。
and Yahiko saved us.
人の食べ物を盗んでまで。
He stole food from others to feed us.
ボクは ただ２人を守りたい。
I just want to protect those two.
どんなに痛みが伴うことが
あったとしても。
No matter what kind of pain
I have to endure.
そうか。
I see.
"TALES OF A GUTSY NINJA BY JIRAIYA"
水遁！ 水乱波!!
Water Style: Raging Waves!
紙手裏剣！
風遁！ 烈風掌!!
Paper Shuriken!
Wind Style: Gale Palm!
やった！
We did it!
どうよ 先生！
ワシの影分身を
やるまでになるとはのぉ。
How's that, Sensei?!
You're even able to take down
my Shadow Clone now, eh?
これで 安心して里に帰れる。
Now I can return to my village
without any worries.
え？
- Huh?
これからは
お前たちだけでやっていけ。
You are on your own from now on.
この３年間 よくがんばったの。
You've done well these past three years!
おっと 泣くな弥彦。
弱虫だと思われるぞ。
Don't cry, Yahiko.
Or people will call you a coward.
小南 お前は美人になるだろう。
大きくなったら また会おうの。
Konan... You're gonna grow up
to be a beauty.
I'm looking forward to seeing you again.
この国は貧しいし この先
悲しいことも多々あるだろう。
This is a poor land.
And there's more sadness
and tough times up ahead.
だが 今度はお前たちの力で
この国を変えていけ。
But now, you have the strength
to change this land.
長門 お前たちは成長した。
Nagato... You three have grown up.
そうだろ？
Don't you agree?
(長門)ありがとう 先生。
Thank you, Sensei.
＜自来也が里に帰ってからも
第三次忍界大戦は続いていた＞
Even after Jiraiya returned to the village,
the Third Great Ninja War raged on.
いいな 綱手！ 大蛇丸！
Tsunade! Orochimaru! Ready?!
あぁ！
ふむ！
Yeah!
(３人)口寄せの術！
Summoning
Jutsu!
＜木ノ葉の里の三忍は
多くの戦いで功をあげ➡
The Hidden Leaf's Sannin distinguished
themselves in many battles...
伝説の名を
欲しいままにしていった＞
leaving legends in their wake.
(綱手)この戦い
いつまで続くのか…。
All this fighting...
How long must it continue?
どうやれば
終わらせられるのか…。
What must be done to stop the war?
フン…
そんな方法あるわけないわね。
Humph... As if there's a way to stop it.
憎しみは憎しみを
生んでいくからね。
Hate only gives birth
to even more hate.
そんな！
But...!
方法はわからん。
だが 必ず平和をつかむ。
I don't know how to stop it.
But peace will certainly come.
そう信じる者がいるかぎり
希望はあると思うがのぉ。
As long as there are those who
believe that, there is hope.
(自来也)おぉ どうした？
Oh, what's the matter?
どうした？
What's wrong?
あの子たちが死んだ…。
Those three have died.
ワシは 正しい選択肢を選ぼうと
努力してきた。
I've tried my best to make
the right choices.
それが 自分に与えられた
運命だと思ってな。
I believed that was what destiny
had in store for me.
自来也…。
そして やっと➡
Jiraiya...
正しい選択ができたと
思い込んでおった。
And finally...
I thought I did what was right.
しかし
また違っておったのかもしれん。
But perhaps,
I was wrong yet again.
きっと見つかる…
信じてさえいれば。
You'll find it
as long as you keep believing.
そうじゃの… まだまだ
道半ばということかのぉ。
Yes... I guess I'm still in
the middle of my journey.
＜永きにわたる
第三次忍界大戦を➡
The Third Great Ninja War dragged on
木ノ葉の勝利に導いたのも また➡
and the one who guided
Hidden Leaf Village to victory
自来也の優秀な弟子の１人
波風ミナトであった＞
was another one of Jiraiya's disciples...
Namikaze Minato.
長かった… 長すぎた。
That was long. Too long...
これから どうする？
そうだのう…。
What will you do from now on?
また 旅に出るかのぉ。
Let's see...
Maybe set out on another journey.
どこかで この世を変える弟子に
出会えるかもしれんからのぉ。
Maybe I'll find a disciple who
can change the world.
それが お前の…
自来也の運命なのか？
Is that your destiny?
The destiny of Jiraiya?
まぁ そういうことだのぉ。
Well, I guess you could say that...
フン… 物好きね。
Humph... What a strange man you are.
お主は 己が忍道➡
Hmm? You walk the path of the ninja.
誰かに引き継いでもらいたいとは
思わないか？
Don't you want someone
to take over after you?
世にある
すべての術を集め 究めること。
To gather all the jutsu in this world
and master them...
私の願いは それだけ。
That is my only goal.
たとえ 術を究めようとも
人の命は 永遠ではない！
Even if you master them all,
humans are not immortal.
そうじゃ！
フン…。
She's right.
それは どうかしら？
I wonder about that...
"TALES OF A GUTSY NINJA"
あきらめろ。
ひと言 いいか？
Give it up.
聞く気はねえ!!
Can I say one thing?
I don't care to listen!!
もう くたばれ。
Die already!
オレがあきらめるのを…。
Give up...
あきらめろ！
...on me giving up!
くっ… オレを倒しても➡
また 次の刺客が この里を襲う。
Even if you bring me down,
another assassin
will attack the village...
フフフ… オレたちが
呪われた忍の世界に➡
As long as we are cursed to live
in this ninja world,
生きているかぎり 平穏は… ない。
there will be no peace.
なら…
オレが その呪いを解いてやる！
Then... I'll break that curse!
平和ってのが もしあるなら➡
If there is such a thing as peace,
I'll seize it!
オレが それを つかみ取ってやる！
オレは あきらめない！
I'll never give up!
キサマは？
Wh-Who are you...?
オレの名は…。
My name is...
おぉっ ワシの 『ド根性忍伝』を
読んでくれておるのか？
Oh... you were reading my
"Tales of a Gutsy Ninja"?
しかし 処女作だし
まだ文章も稚拙で➡
But it's my first published work.
あんまり 出来は
よくないんだがのぉ！
The sentences are childish
and I didn't do a good job.
いや そんなことはないです。
No, I don't think so.
This tale is wonderful!
この物語は すばらしいです！
ほぅ…。
エピソードが 先生の数々の伝説に
なぞらえてあって➡
Oh...?
Each chapter reads like one
of your numerous legendary exploits.
なにか 自伝小説っぽくて。
It's almost like an autobiography.
いや だがの…
まったく売れんかった。
But... it didn't sell at all.
次回作は お得意の
エロ要素でも入れてみるかのぉ。
For my next one, I think I'll add some
sexy elements to spice it up a bit.
この本の主人公…。
The main character of this book...
最後まで あきらめなかった
ところが かっこよかった。
I thought his determination to
never give up was really cool.
先生らしいですね。 この主人公。
He's a lot like you, Sensei.
そ… そうかのぉ？
Y-You think so...?
で… オレ 思ったんです！
ん？
So I was thinking.
今度 生まれてくる子供も
こんな主人公みたいな➡
Huh?
I really hope my unborn child
can become a ninja
忍になってくれたらいいなって。
just like this main character!
だから この小説の主人公の名前
いただいてもいいですか？
Which is why I'd like your permission
to name my son after him.
お… おい！
そんなんでいいのか？
H-Hey! Are you sure?
ラーメン食いながら
適当に決めた名前だぞ。
It's just a random name that I thought up
while eating ramen.
(クシナ)ナルト…。
ステキな名前です。
Naruto...
It's a wonderful name.
クシナ…。
Kushina...
ハハ… ったく…
ってことは ワシが名付け親かの？
Cripes... So that makes me
his godfather?
ワシなんかで ホントにいいのか？
Are you really sure about this?
先生だからこそです。
You are my sensei!
本当の忍の才能をもつ
立派な忍者で➡
And you are a great ninja who possesses
the true talent of a ninja!
あなたほどの忍は
いませんからね。
There's no other like you.
＜ その後も
自来也は 運命を求め➡
Even after this...
さまよい 旅を続けた。
Jiraiya continued his journey
in search of his destiny.
自来也が 木ノ葉隠れの里で
ナルトと出会うことになるのは➡
It would be a little later before
Jiraiya would meet Naruto
もう少し あとのことである＞
in the Village Hidden in the Leaves.
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
life always throws you curveballs and the reason of that is
yo kono yo wa hitosujinawa de ikanai sore wa naze nara
it's a test made by God so that's why it's quite hard
kamisama ga tsukutta tesuto dakara muzukashii nda
arts? science? or rather how about ethics?
bunkei rikei mushiro doutoku kimi nara kore wo dou toku
this is just like life so put your heart and soul into seriousness
kore wa maru de jinsei dakara uchikomu shinken ni
we worry ourselves lose ourselves and we keep asking ourselves questions
bokura wa nayamu mayou nandomo jibun ni toikakeru
we aren't one and relentesly persue our search for answers
hitotsu ja nai kotae sagashi gamushara ni oikakeru
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
the current me would tell me that if I was from the future
mirai no bokura nara ima no boku ni oshiete agerareru
you should keep pursuing it until your efforts change yourself
kimi no doryoku ga jishin ni kawaru toki made oitsuzukereba ii
(銀時)え～ ペンネーム…
キャサリンのネコ耳は 史上最悪➡
Next Episode
What's going on here?!
最強の兵器であるさんの質問。
It's great that I got in so easily,
「『銀魂』は 何がしたいのですか？
but who is this Pain
that everybody speaks of?!
やりたいことが
よくわかりません。
このアニメの ゴールが見当たりません」。
All I get from the villagers are
vague descriptions such as "god" or "angel".
はい ズバリ お答えしましょう。
And I don't know the whereabouts
of the former village leader,
オレも わかりません。
いやぁ ２年半もやってんのに➡
Hanzo of the Salamander.
But there's no time to waste...
いまだ
こういうハガキが来る 体たらく…。
Guess I'll go with that plan!
Infiltrate!
The Village Hidden in
the Rain
Next time: "Infiltrate! The Village Hidden in the Rain"